# TODD F. BARTELT

toddfbartelt@gmail.com | 913-636-7276 | Lenexa, KS 66215 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/todd-bartelt Github: https://github.com/bartelto | Portfolio: https://toddbartelt.com

### **Summary**

**Full Stack Web Developer** with 10+ years' experience in desktop software development and graphic design. Blends a creative knack with a sharp eye for detail in developing user-friendly applications. An insightful leader, dedicated to exceeding expectations while ensuring that the whole team crosses the finish line together.

### **Technical Skills**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, C#, C++, VB.NET, SQL, MongoDB

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Node.js, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Firebase

**Applications:** Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro X

### **Relevant Experience**

## Director of Engagement Kaw Prairie Community Church

8/2017 - 3/2019

Lenexa, KS

Oversaw participant engagement, volunteer placement, small groups and discipleship classes, as well as many aspects of communication, administration and first impressions. Key Accomplishments:

- Created and maintained "Serve-opoly", a Monopoly-branded info station where church attendees could browse open service opportunities, find contact information for leaders, and volunteer for roles.
- Led the adoption of project management software (Asana) by the staff team, improving accountability, follow-through and communication.

## Project Analyst AmerisourceBergen Corporation

1/2014 - 8/2017

Chesterbrook, PA

Collected and analyzed project requirements; recommended and designed software and process changes for warehouse management; tested new software solutions. Key Accomplishments:

- Took the lead in understanding the new legal and technical requirements of a project to track individual items through the distribution network; became the team's go-to expert.
- Hand-picked by a vice president to research, using test and production data, a possible expansion of a manual sorting process at the company's national distribution center.

Software Engineer 9/2009 - 10/2013
Cl³ Integrators Lenexa, KS

Programmed, configured, upgraded and maintained a variety of software products controlling surveillance, access control, and HVAC for multiple customers. Provided both on-site and remote support during new construction projects and while troubleshooting issues. *Key Accomplishments*:

- Integrated a major customer's surveillance and access control systems with a custom user interface developed in Microsoft Visual Studio (C#).
- Exuded a calm confidence and a can-do attitude when on site with customers, thereby forging a strong sense of trust with both customers and managers alike.

### **Projects**

Game Spark | https://github.com/bartelto/project-2 | https://bartelto.github.io/project-1/

- Constructed a social media platform for table-top game enthusiasts. The app enables each user to set up a profile specifying the game(s) that they are interested in playing and matches them to other users with the same interests.
- Individual contributions: designing the MySQL database schema; creating the Sequelize
  models to interface with the database; and writing the HTML and API routes for the
  app's Node/Express server and most of the front-end AJAX calls to the server.
- Technologies used: Javascript, jQuery, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MySQL, Node, Express, Board Game Atlas API (<a href="https://www.boardgameatlas.com">https://www.boardgameatlas.com</a>)

War of Words | https://github.com/bartelto/project-1 | https://bartelto.github.io/project-1/

- Developed a two-player online version of the card game War. Includes an in-game chat feature with synthesized voice that players can use to hurl insults at each other.
- Individual contributions: a waiting-room style system for meeting other players and challenging them to games (using Firebase); designing the styling for the playing cards; creating a simple chat system (using both text and synthesized voice) and player-to-player game coordination via Firebase.
- Technologies used: Javascript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap, Deck of Cards API (<a href="https://deckofcardsapi.com">https://deckofcardsapi.com</a>), Responsive Voice API (<a href="https://responsivevoice.org">https://deckofcardsapi.com</a>), Adorable Avatars API (<a href="http://avatars.adorable.io">http://avatars.adorable.io</a>)

#### Education

Web Development Certificate: University of Kansas, Overland Park, KS

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical development skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js & React.

Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering: University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI

Bachelor of Arts - Mathematics and Physics: Luther College, Decorah, IA